<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/INSO-Blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/INSO-Blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-12-01T15:45:49-04:00</updated><id>/INSO-Blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">INSO4101 Class Blog</title><subtitle>A blog for what was learned in the INSO4101 class in UPRM. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Sequence charts</title><link href="/INSO-Blog/2019/11/24/Sequence-Charts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sequence charts" /><published>2019-11-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-11-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/INSO-Blog/2019/11/24/Sequence%20Charts</id><content type="html" xml:base="/INSO-Blog/2019/11/24/Sequence-Charts.html"></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Petri nets</title><link href="/INSO-Blog/2019/11/12/Petri-Nets.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Petri nets" /><published>2019-11-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-11-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/INSO-Blog/2019/11/12/Petri%20Nets</id><content type="html" xml:base="/INSO-Blog/2019/11/12/Petri-Nets.html"></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Automata</title><link href="/INSO-Blog/2019/11/07/Automata.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Automata" /><published>2019-11-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-11-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/INSO-Blog/2019/11/07/Automata</id><content type="html" xml:base="/INSO-Blog/2019/11/07/Automata.html"></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Modularization</title><link href="/INSO-Blog/2019/10/28/Modularization.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Modularization" /><published>2019-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/INSO-Blog/2019/10/28/Modularization</id><content type="html" xml:base="/INSO-Blog/2019/10/28/Modularization.html"></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Domains part 2</title><link href="/INSO-Blog/2019/10/18/Domains-Part-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domains part 2" /><published>2019-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/INSO-Blog/2019/10/18/Domains%20Part%202</id><content type="html" xml:base="/INSO-Blog/2019/10/18/Domains-Part-2.html"></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Domains</title><link href="/INSO-Blog/2019/10/10/Domains.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domains" /><published>2019-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/INSO-Blog/2019/10/10/Domains</id><content type="html" xml:base="/INSO-Blog/2019/10/10/Domains.html"></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Time management</title><link href="/INSO-Blog/2019/10/03/Time-Management.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Time management" /><published>2019-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/INSO-Blog/2019/10/03/Time%20Management</id><content type="html" xml:base="/INSO-Blog/2019/10/03/Time-Management.html"></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Importance of planning</title><link href="/INSO-Blog/2019/09/29/Importance-of-Planning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Importance of planning" /><published>2019-09-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/INSO-Blog/2019/09/29/Importance%20of%20Planning</id><content type="html" xml:base="/INSO-Blog/2019/09/29/Importance-of-Planning.html"></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Logic and math</title><link href="/INSO-Blog/2019/09/18/Logic-and-Math.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Logic and math" /><published>2019-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/INSO-Blog/2019/09/18/Logic%20and%20Math</id><content type="html" xml:base="/INSO-Blog/2019/09/18/Logic-and-Math.html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;Algebra and mathematical logic are the more formal ways of defining what wants to be built. Math is universal and with rather small background in engineering and programming a person could analyze the models that are presented. The logic allows the program to be checked for any basic logical problems that may arrise. This may be a simple boolean but sometimes the underlying algorithm is not logically or mathenatically possible. Utilizing this tool helps mitigate this problem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;Since math is fundamental in every part of our life it is essential. Some of the ways the logic and math may be used is by making propositional logic or using previously established axioms. In addition, any mathematical explanation should not be overly complicated and should be appropriately quantifiable. Every technical aspect has some underlying math and logic built into it even if it is not explicitly written.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Algebra and mathematical logic are the more formal ways of defining what wants to be built. Math is universal and with rather small background in engineering and programming a person could analyze the models that are presented. The logic allows the program to be checked for any basic logical problems that may arrise. This may be a simple boolean but sometimes the underlying algorithm is not logically or mathenatically possible. Utilizing this tool helps mitigate this problem Since math is fundamental in every part of our life it is essential. Some of the ways the logic and math may be used is by making propositional logic or using previously established axioms. In addition, any mathematical explanation should not be overly complicated and should be appropriately quantifiable. Every technical aspect has some underlying math and logic built into it even if it is not explicitly written.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Documentation</title><link href="/INSO-Blog/2019/09/09/Documentation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Documentation" /><published>2019-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/INSO-Blog/2019/09/09/Documentation</id><content type="html" xml:base="/INSO-Blog/2019/09/09/Documentation.html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;Documentation is the fundamental and backbone of any Software Engineering project. Without documentation the planning of the application will be much more complicated or maybe even impossible if it’s a project that is starting out. If it’s a project that is fully developed than it is still important to understand the whole backbone or specifics about the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;Without appropriate documentation any engineer working on the project might take way longer to develop or understand. This is time and resources wasted for the engineer and the company that he/she might be working for and in a modern world we live in it is extremely important to be efficient as possible. This may be the difference between a successful company or an average or bad company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;The following has to be understood by anyone related to the project even if they don’t have knowledge in software engineering. This removes any limitation and getting too involved in coding errors or differences in opinions. This also helps other domain experts give their opinion about a subject that the coders or project managers might not have knowledge in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;Each document may vary widely between each project. Some projects require every single detail to be laid out because not doing so my result in life’s lost or an extraordinary amount of money to be wasted. It can also be seen as a type of introduction for the whole document so any reader can get a feel for what they will be analyzing if they are new to the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;As we have seen documentation is very important in software engineering and most posts will continue on ideas and details about this topic.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Documentation is the fundamental and backbone of any Software Engineering project. Without documentation the planning of the application will be much more complicated or maybe even impossible if it’s a project that is starting out. If it’s a project that is fully developed than it is still important to understand the whole backbone or specifics about the code. Without appropriate documentation any engineer working on the project might take way longer to develop or understand. This is time and resources wasted for the engineer and the company that he/she might be working for and in a modern world we live in it is extremely important to be efficient as possible. This may be the difference between a successful company or an average or bad company. The following has to be understood by anyone related to the project even if they don’t have knowledge in software engineering. This removes any limitation and getting too involved in coding errors or differences in opinions. This also helps other domain experts give their opinion about a subject that the coders or project managers might not have knowledge in. Each document may vary widely between each project. Some projects require every single detail to be laid out because not doing so my result in life’s lost or an extraordinary amount of money to be wasted. It can also be seen as a type of introduction for the whole document so any reader can get a feel for what they will be analyzing if they are new to the project. As we have seen documentation is very important in software engineering and most posts will continue on ideas and details about this topic.</summary></entry></feed>